Tyra Hans Software Developer

Nairobi, Kenya (+254) 705834383 tyrahans17@gmail.com https://github.com/Tyra-hans https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyra-hans/

Personal Summary

Well rounded developer with object-oriented, user-centered design and experience ranging from static web pages (HTML, CSS) to software systems, front end and back end development.

Highlighted applications

Imprint Africa company website / HTML CSS Javascript http://demo.imprintafrica.co.ke/

May 2020

A company website with elaborate design and user experience.

- Illustrated services offered in simple vector graphics
- Interactive design with use of pre-loaders and on-hover functionalities
- Functional form for newsletters and contact

Stock Management System / Python Back end developer https://tastefrique.herokuapp.com/accounts/login/?next=/ January 2020

A multi-user stock management system that consolidates a company's records on activities pertaining to the company. Key features include exporting records to Excel format, stock notifications and optimization, CRUD operations - as per user permissions.

 Architected SQL database models, implemented business logic in Django to generate stock notifications and testing of the application by use of Unittests and Django coverage.

Technical Skills

Proficient: HTML, CSS(Bootstrap), Python(Django), PostgreSQL, unit tests, Agile methodologies.

Conversant: Javascript(Angular), Python(Flask), Gunicorn, DjangoRest Framework, heroku

Personal Skills

- Team player that enjoys collaborative thinking and activities.
- Quickstudy and excited to learn new things and polish existing knowledge.
- Tactical thinker with the ability to break down and solve problems.
- Self-reliant and requires minimal supervision.

_

Professional History

Imprint Africa

A tech firm keen on availing technology to SMEs whose lack of access keeps them from participating in global trade and scaling to their fullest potential.

March 2020 to date

Key responsibilities :

Web development and design

Artiv Music School

A music and arts school located along Ngong Road , Ndemi Lane.

July 2017 to date

Key responsibilities:

- Supervision of students
- Code instructor
- Drums teacher
- Updating studio website and management of studio projects

Nyali Music School

A music school located in Nyali, Mombasa.

May 2018 to July 2019

Key responsibilities:

- Supervision of students
- Drums teacher

Education

Moringa School

A fully immersive Software Development course.

August 2019 to January 2020

Key Learnings:

- Scrum and agile tactics
- Test Driven Development
- · Object-oriented and user-centered design

University of Nairobi

Bsc Arts in Political Science.

March 2018 to date

Our Lady of Mercy, South B

KCSE certificate 2016

2016

Interests

 Music: Participated in Sarafina Musical as a drummer at the Kenya National Theatre and

Music Freedom Day for Turning Tables Kenya.

• Sports: Participated in Soccer at Ligi Ndogo and basketball in highschool and other

tournaments such as Greensports games.

 Art: Participated in Kenahica - a highschool art competition in 2014 and 2015 and

emerged best graphic designer.